<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-27T23:42:15+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons</title><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.16</title><link href="/blog/2019/02/27/version-16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.16" /><published>2019-02-27T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-27T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2019/02/27/version-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2019/02/27/version-16.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s version 16! Wow. Whoa! We’ve come such a long way since that janky 7drl prototype!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This update is huge! Let’s see what’s new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/amdicenow.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Story&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons finally has a story. We’ve been talking about this on the team for months and months, so it’s really amazing to finally have it in the game. It’s writen by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hollygramazio&quot;&gt;Holly Gramazio&lt;/a&gt; (whose previous digital games writing includes the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://severalbees.com/blackbird/how-to-be-a-blackbird.html&quot;&gt;How to be a Blackbird&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://onenightinskegness.com/&quot;&gt;One Night in Skegness&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want the story in Dicey Dungeons to be minimal, funny, and seemlessly part of the world. I wanted it to bring all the different parts of the game together, and make everything feel more connected - and I couldn’t be happier with how it’s turning out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version just has three character introduction cutscenes, some “introduction” lines by Lady Luck, and very occasional monster “last words”. There’s more coming, though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/bambam.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Tutorial&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also finally have a tutorial! This will appear in the game the first time you play the first Warrior episode. (we still don’t have quest progression, though, sorry)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal with the tutorial was to make a kind of “youtube annotations” style thing, where you can just play as normal and little pop ups appear to tell you stuff from time to time. Depending on how this goes down, I might do similar ones for the other five characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/newsnap.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Return of the Jester&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jester’s back! Ahhhh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/blog/2019/02/design-diary-the-jester/&quot;&gt;a LOT&lt;/a&gt; about this already recently, so I’ll just say, it’s really good to have them back. The new Jester features five quests so far (including the temporary “classic hardmode”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/youchooseyoulose.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;A huge design revamp&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve getting closer and closer to the end of development, and I’m getting to the point where I want to “settle” the design of certain elements. There was a lot of stuff that I haven’t touched for months - so for this update, I decided to do a complete top to bottom revamp of everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the biggest actual change with this update - virtually everything in the game has had a tweak, from dungeon generation and equipment distribution, to level up rewards, to enemy design - it amounts to hundreds of tiny tiny changes. Feedback welcome - I’m sure I’ll be iterating on all this stuff a lot more before launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to pick a few big things in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dungeons now have six floors instead of 5, making things very slightly longer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All characters have new level up rewards and new level pacing, designed to tune things ever so slightly harder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The game now has occasional “Super Enemies” - enemies that appear 1 level higher than usual, with remixed equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In particular, Inventor equipment distribution has changed &lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And an example of a few random small things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed “are you sure?” style prompts from almost everywhere - when buying equipment, collecting chests, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Counter Spell works for any dice now by default, and the upgraded version is useable twice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upgraded Healing Crystals cure poison.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New map blueprint layouts for dungeons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inventor doesn’t start with scrap metal anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Rat King is back, with a new design.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dragon has had a complete redesign, and is possibly the hardest boss now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Renamed “Quests” to “Episodes”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Witch can now get up to four prepared spells, or one prepared slot and three upgraded slots.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed Fuse, added new “Ruby Weapon” to Robot’s “You Choose, You Lose” episode. (previously named Dice for a Price)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redesigned Vampiric Tendencies with a focus on a new piece of equipment, “Venus Fly Trap”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed the equipment screen, finally!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process included doing a complete audit of every enemy in the game, again - which I’ll be posting about on my blog soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/scripts.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;More Modding Support&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version of the game moves a huge amount of new things into scripts and data files that modders can modify. Including!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Script hooks at several points throughout the game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level generation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User variables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to use &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; piece of equipment as a skillcard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this, of course, runs on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/larsiusprime/polymod&quot;&gt;Lars’ polymod system&lt;/a&gt;, and uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HaxeFoundation/hscript&quot;&gt;hscript powered scripting&lt;/a&gt;. Honestly, I think this update should bring the game up 95% of what modders have been asking for. There’s a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of new stuff to play with here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/stereohead.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Music&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some brand new tunes this time around, as well as some updates to old songs, and remix ideas that Niamh is trying out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version16/shopa.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;An Irish Translation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in time for Seachtain na Gaeilge, I’m really proud to debut our new Irish translation, by Mícheál J. Ó Meachair and Kevin P. Scannell of &lt;a href=&quot;https://riomhacadamh.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Ríomhacadamh&lt;/a&gt;. (I’ll be putting together a small Irish testing group very soon if there are any gaeilgeoirs out there are interested in having a look - &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/email/&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A heads up that ALL translations this time are a little out of date - i.e. all the new cutscene text is in English. We’re waiting to finalise the game’s script before we get all that translated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.17?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I have some big news on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;v0.17 is &lt;em&gt;probably going to be the last alpha&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep! After v0.17, the next version will be v1.0, which will remain on &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanagh.itch.io/dicey-dungeons&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;, but also, finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/861540/Dicey_Dungeons/&quot;&gt;coming to steam&lt;/a&gt;. (More information about when coming as soon as I know!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think with this update, we’re now far enough along that the end is very much in sight! v0.17 will likely be shorter and smaller than the last two updates, and more about getting the game stable while the team knuckles down and finishes the game. We’re doing it this way so that we can just focus as much as possible on the final version, but also, we wanna hold some surprises back for the launch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I am planning to put together a smaller testing group for the release canditates. If you’ve been an active player since the early version, I might be getting in touch soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing. I hope you enjoy the new version!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s version 16! Wow. Whoa! We’ve come such a long way since that janky 7drl prototype!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.15</title><link href="/blog/2018/12/25/version-15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.15" /><published>2018-12-25T01:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T01:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/12/25/version-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/12/25/version-15.html">&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas, everyone! Ho ho ho! I bring presents!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since the last Dicey Dungeons update. Thank you for your patience! The whole team has been working really hard on this one, and we’re very excited to finally share it. Let’s see what’s new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/rosebattle.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Quests&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heart of this update is the game’s new quest system. Quests are alternate game modes for each character, evolved from the old guild system. They’re about showing you a new side of each character, making you think differently about them, while providing some interesting challenges on the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each quest is a tweak to the basic rules - there’s one for the Warrior that makes you lose max HP when you level up, one for the thief that lets you keep enemy equipment, one for the Witch that gives you a predictable sequence of dice, and lots more. I’m eventually planning to have 36 of them, six for each character (this build has 20).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still to come is the “progression” side of this system, where quests, characters and content are unlocked as you play through the game. Since this is a very separate problem to the actual quest design, I figured I’d take the time to think about it properly - so for this version, everything is open and unlocked right from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/cleverhandyman.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Smarter Enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my own time since the last update was spent on this: figuring out how to make the enemies smarter. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/blog/2018/12/how-enemy-ai-works-in-dicey-dungeons/&quot;&gt;very in-depth blog post about it here&lt;/a&gt;, but basically: you can now just rely on the enemies in Dicey Dungeons to make smart moves - no more exploits and weird edge cases. It just works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/youwin.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Lots of art improvements&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last update, Marlowe has been focused on doing a huge polish pass on all the game’s artwork! This includes new animated backgrounds for every scene, animated player characters, and just lots and lots of subtle improvements to basically everything in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, thanks to our programmer Justo, we now have proper 4K support! If you’re playing the game on a 4K screen, it should automatically detect that and use 4K textures everywhere! (You can try toggling these on and off by going into the settings on the main menu.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/shovel.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Tooltips, Enemy Move previews, and animation speed controls&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not planning to tackle the actual tutorial until the next version of the game, but this version finally introduces a few very helpful tutorial-esque features for new players. You can now mouse over status effects to see what they do, preview the enemy moves on your own turn, and slow down the combat animations until you get the hang of how things work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/scripts.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Underlying tech improvements&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This probably won’t matter to most players, but anyone interested in modding should be very excited about this update! This version moves lots of the game’s internal data into spreadsheets, making it possible to access and modify all sorts of things that weren’t possible before - quest data, level up rewards, rule tweaks, equipment actions, and more. Even better, lots of this runs off a fully programmable &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HaxeFoundation/hscript&quot;&gt;hscript interpreter&lt;/a&gt; - so you can, for example, design equipment that messes with in game variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation for all this isn’t there yet, and the in-game editor is still running behind the what the mod system is actually capable of - but if that doesn’t deter you, then check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version15/languages.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Translations&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two new translations this time, Japanese and Traditional Chinese! Our Japanese translation is by Go Endo of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kakehashigames.com/&quot;&gt;Kakehashi Games&lt;/a&gt;, while our Traditional Chinese translation is by whiteblack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, all translations are in alpha, and some are more complete than others! One of the great things about doing localisations for a game while it’s in development is that I can get feedback on it as we go, and iterate on that to make all of the localisations as great as they can possibly be. If you have any feedback on any of the translations, I’d love to hear it! (I have a place to give &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues/512&quot;&gt;feedback for translation issues here&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.16?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m planning to basically take the rest of the year off now, and start thinking about v0.16 in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big thing on my radar is to finally start making some progress on our story, and maybe adding some very short cutscenes to the game. I’m excited to see how that goes! We’re also planning to reintroduce and finalise the Jester as one of the main cast (they’re absent from this build while I try to figure them out). Also, very excited to show you what &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marlowedobbe/status/1062164254642466817&quot;&gt;Chipzel’s been working on recently&lt;/a&gt; for the audio side of things…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve somehow found yourself reading this blog post without having played the game, then I’ve got good news! The alpha of Dicey Dungeons is currently part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanagh.itch.io/dicey-dungeons&quot;&gt;itch.io’s winter sale, with 20% off!&lt;/a&gt; This is your last chance to get the game cheap, since the game won’t be on sale again until after it launches!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing. See you next year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Merry Christmas, everyone! Ho ho ho! I bring presents!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.14</title><link href="/blog/2018/10/13/version-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.14" /><published>2018-10-13T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-10-13T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/10/13/version-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/10/13/version-14.html">&lt;p&gt;Surprise! It’s v0.14 of Dicey Dungeons! I know, it’s a saturday, and v0.13 was only two weeks ago, but after getting the final character up and running, I thought it was a good time to stop and polish up a few things. This build is mostly about polishing up some rough edges, and consolidating what we’ve got so far - but there’s some cool new stuff as well! Let’s have a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version14/finalecard.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Trading Posts, Booster Packs and Finale Cards&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying out a couple of new systems this time around, the biggest of which is the Trading Post. Trading Posts will offer to swap something you have for something else - usually something rare or unusual…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made some improvements to the Jester, although it’s still in Alpha for this version. The Jester can now finds Booster Packs, which offer a combination of three cards, some good, some bad - take all of them or none of them. Also, I’ve introduced &lt;em&gt;Finale Cards&lt;/em&gt;! Finale Cards are powerful cards that only appear for the Jester if you use everything else in your hand in a single turn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also made dozens of little changes to all the characters, including changes to starting equipment and item distribution. Still planning a major design pass soon, but these improvements should help things a little until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version14/scathach.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;All enemies are animated!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of art edits in the this build! In particular, every enemy in the game is animated now! Ahhhh! And…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New combat music, new sound effects!&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chipzel’s got an awesome new combat track for this version, but that’s not all - now that we’ve moved to desktop builds, we don’t have to worry so much about file size limits. So, this build includes all eight work in progress tracks that we’ve had over the last three versions, v0.11, v0.12 and v0.13!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these are rougher than others, of course - they’re all at an unfinished stage - but I think having all of them in the game really makes things come together! This version also has a bunch of new sound effects, and remasters of sounds from previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version14/soytari.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Turkish Translation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One new translation this time around, Turkish! (random aside: Turkish has a cool &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.i18nguy.com/unicode/turkish-i18n.html&quot;&gt;string encoding&lt;/a&gt; tech challenge that was pretty fun to figure out!). Like Portuguese, Italian, Polish, Russian and Brazilian Portuguese, the Turkish translation is handled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/company/eds-wordland-ltd&quot;&gt;EDS Wordland&lt;/a&gt; and their international team of translators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a quicker than usual turn around on localisations this time, so I didn’t have time to get the newer Jester content translated yet. We’ll catch up for the next version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.15?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game’s next milestone is the quest system, and we’ve been making some &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marlowedobbe/status/1048659008196763648&quot;&gt;pretty exciting progress&lt;/a&gt; on that. Looking forward to sharing more of that once it’s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in the next update!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Surprise! It’s v0.14 of Dicey Dungeons! I know, it’s a saturday, and v0.13 was only two weeks ago, but after getting the final character up and running, I thought it was a good time to stop and polish up a few things. This build is mostly about polishing up some rough edges, and consolidating what we’ve got so far - but there’s some cool new stuff as well! Let’s have a look!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.13</title><link href="/blog/2018/09/28/version-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.13" /><published>2018-09-28T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/09/28/version-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/09/28/version-13.html">&lt;p&gt;Announcing v0.13 of Dicey Dungeons! This one’s a big one, so let’s jump right in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version13/jestergameplay.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Jester&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sixth and final character in Dicey Dungeons is &lt;em&gt;The Jester&lt;/em&gt;! I’ve known since the early weeks of development that I wanted to make a deckbuilding class for Dicey Dungeons, but it wasn’t until now that I had enough pieces in place to make it all happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Jester finds equipment, it gets added to a deck that you draw from randomly. You can have three pieces of equipment in play at any time, and you keep drawing until you can’t play any more cards. The key thing that makes this all work, though, is the &lt;em&gt;Snap!&lt;/em&gt; mechanic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Jester has matching pieces of equipment, you can &lt;em&gt;Snap!&lt;/em&gt; them and convert them into new dice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like how this character shaped up! I’m presenting it as an “alpha” in this version, mostly because I think there’s a lot more room to explore here, which I’m very excited to do over the next few versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version13/jesteranimate.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Animations and overworld sprites&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing animations! About half the enemies are currently animated, and the rest are coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the combat animations, we also have adorable new overworld sprites!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Music and sound effects&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have new music and sound effects! This time around we reworked our sound tech a little to support different sound effects for different equipment. There’s also a new work in progress combat track!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version13/mods.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Modding API&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major development for people interested in modding: this version introduces a whole new modding API by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/larsiusprime&quot;&gt;Lars Doucet&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, modding is kind of a three part problem - first, you need the infrastructure to support swapping in custom assets, then, you need to expose stuff from the game into files that can be modified, and thirdly, ideally, you need an editor that can modify those files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part one. Lars has implemented his &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/larsiusprime/polymod&quot;&gt;polymod framework&lt;/a&gt; into Dicey Dungeons! It makes it possible to override and append Dicey Dungeon’s assets, and combine multiple mods together! It’s the start of something very cool, and I’m looking forward to seeing what people manage to do with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version13/translations.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;11 translations, and counting&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version of Dicey Dungeons brings SIX new translations! The Spanish translation is by &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextlevellocalization.com/index.html&quot;&gt;Felipe Mercader&lt;/a&gt;, while Portuguese, Italian, Polish, Russian and Brazilian Portuguese are by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mobygames.com/company/eds-wordland-ltd&quot;&gt;EDS Wordland&lt;/a&gt; and their international team of translators!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I’m still planning a couple more languages - Turkish, Japanese, Traditional Chinese and Irish, and then that’s probably it!)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Native Versions&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, v0.13 introduces native Windows, Mac and Linux versions of Dicey Dungeons! We are now abandoning HTML5 builds, which I think we’ve very much outgrown now. From here until we launch on steam, we’re going to be doing desktop builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new versions were made possible by our new programmer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jdbaudi&quot;&gt;Justo Delgado&lt;/a&gt;, who joined the Dicey Dungeons team a few weeks ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.14?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jester is the final character - so, this marks a major milestone in the game. From here on out, my focus is going to be on tying everything together - which includes quest systems for repeated playthroughs, end game content, and in particular, lots of work to deepen and expand on what’s already in there. I see the six characters as they currently are as rough sketches - and I’m very, very excited to start filling out the details. I wanna make this game as great as I know it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This milestone does mean that the end is in sight, though, so recently I’ve been doing some serious thinking about when it’s actually going to be finished. I don’t think the late 2018 estimate is likely anymore, but I think we’re seriously looking at a launch early in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing, and I hope you enjoy the new character! See you in the next update!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Announcing v0.13 of Dicey Dungeons! This one’s a big one, so let’s jump right in:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.12</title><link href="/blog/2018/08/31/version-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.12" /><published>2018-08-31T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-31T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/08/31/version-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/08/31/version-12.html">&lt;p&gt;Surprise! It’s version v0.12 of Dicey Dungeons! Let’s see what’s new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version12/newwitch.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;All five characters are playable again&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Witch is back! The Robot too! And so is the editor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty unhappy about having to push this stuff back from v0.11, so I’m really, really glad to see em back in the game. The Witch, in particular, is still my favourite character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version12/robotvkraken.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Music&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chipzel’s been super busy over the last couple of weeks, and has two new tracks this time! A new combat track, and a new Boss theme! I’ve basically been listening to both on a loop now for last few weeks :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version12/greenforest.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Art&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marlowe’s been busy too! This version has lots of new Art - new combat backgrounds for every location, coloured in character art to replace the previous sketches, and little improvements everywhere. (Marlowe also has a bunch of animations ready to go, but they’re not in the game &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; yet.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version12/girlscout.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couple of brand new enemies this time round, and some existing enemies (like Keymaster, Girl Scout and Crystalina) have had a complete redesign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version12/wordsofmagic.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Now in French&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons is finally available in French, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wom_fr?lang=en&quot;&gt;Words of Magic&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.13?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on the final character, so that’s definitely the focus from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of my time over the last month or so programming, and I think that’s slowed things down a lot. So, I recently put out a &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/blog/2018/08/help-wanted-additional-programmer-for-dicey-dungeons/&quot;&gt;help wanted ad for a programmer&lt;/a&gt; to join the team. The idea is, they can focus on the big tech problems, and I can get back to focusing on design. Applications are open till Monday, so if you’re interested, check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in a few weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Surprise! It’s version v0.12 of Dicey Dungeons! Let’s see what’s new!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.11</title><link href="/blog/2018/08/05/version-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.11" /><published>2018-08-05T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/08/05/version-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/08/05/version-11.html">&lt;p&gt;Whoa, so this build’s really late! Sorry about that! But I’m really excited to finally be able to share it with everyone, at last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I should say right away: this version has less content in it than v0.10 - unfortunately, the Robot and the Witch still need to be implemented in the new engine, and the editor currently isn’t working. All will be making a return soon in future versions, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new version is an absolutely huge overhaul of the entire game. Let’s have a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version11/overworld.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Art and Music&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version of Dicey Dungeons finally introduces the work of &lt;a href=&quot;http://marlowe.dobbe.com/&quot;&gt;Marlowe Dobbe&lt;/a&gt;, the game’s artist, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chipzel.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Chipzel&lt;/a&gt;, the game’s musician!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the design, the music and art in the game is a still a work in progress, and there are placeholders and unfinished pieces everywhere - but this represents a major step forward. I hope you like what our team has put together so far, and the direction we’re headed in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is wishful thinking, but I think getting the game to this point was the really hard bit. Now that we’re finally here, I think things will go &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version11/combat.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Sound Effects&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that’s new to this version: the game finally has sound effects! Yay! They’re also by Chipzel, who’s in charge of all things musical in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version11/newtranslations.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Now in Korean and German&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version has two new translations of the game - Korean, by &lt;a href=&quot;http://imbada.tistory.com/&quot;&gt;BADA IM&lt;/a&gt;, and German, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://indiegametranslations.com/&quot;&gt;Thomas Faust&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I should say that both translations are still in an alpha stage - unfortuantely I wasn’t able to get a playable build to either of them before this release, so they were unable to do things like check text widths or how things look in context. Still, like everything else, they should both get better and better as the game continues to develop!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.12?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a tough update. This probably won’t come as a surprise, but I’ve decided that it’s time to ditch the two week update schedule. It was great early in the project to keep up momentum - but now that we’re nearing the end, I feel like it’s doing more harm than good. Stressed out people don’t do their best work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I’m switching to “regular” updates - which will still come out every couple of weeks or so - but without any advance warning! If you want to get notified of new versions, you can follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanagh.itch.io/dicey-dungeons&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;, twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/terrycavanagh&quot;&gt;@terrycavanagh&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;join the discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For v0.12, I’m excited to be getting back to design, and thinking about the final character. I’m also hoping to reintroduce the Robot and the Witch in our new engine. Thanks for playing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Whoa, so this build’s really late! Sorry about that! But I’m really excited to finally be able to share it with everyone, at last!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.10</title><link href="/blog/2018/07/06/version-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.10" /><published>2018-07-06T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-06T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/07/06/version-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/07/06/version-10.html">&lt;p&gt;Here we are! Version 0.10! The first &lt;strong&gt;commercial&lt;/strong&gt; version! The game’s getting closer and closer to release! Let’s see what’s new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xShpQ85jCVE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons Teaser&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please welcome the rest of team Dicey Dungeons! You can see a little preview of what they’ve been working on in this trailer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/artvart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Art: Marlowe Dobbe&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons new art director is Marlowe Dobbe! Marlowe is an amazing illustrator, animator, and game developer from Portland, Oregon. Her work ranges from animation for the D&amp;amp;D podcast Very Random Encounters, to &lt;a href=&quot;http://marlowe.dobbe.com/lost-wage-rampage&quot;&gt;Lost Wage Rampage&lt;/a&gt;, to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marlowe.dobbe.com/walouija&quot;&gt;WAL-OUIJI board&lt;/a&gt;, which she describes as “a joke that went too far”. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/marlowedobbe/&quot;&gt;check out her instragram here&lt;/a&gt;, where she’ll be posting lots of work in progress Dicey Dungeons artwork over the next few weeks! (she’s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marlowedobbe&quot;&gt;on twitter, here&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/chipzel.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Music: Chipzel&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on music, I’m very excited to announce that I’ve teamed up again with Niamh Houston, aka Chipzel! You might know her from her work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://superhexagon.com/&quot;&gt;Super Hexagon&lt;/a&gt; - but she’s also released three albums and worked on all sorts of cool projects, ranging from an Adventure Time game to a remix for Crypt of the NecroDancer. You can find her work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://chipzel.co.uk/&quot;&gt;http://chipzel.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chipzel/&quot;&gt;follow her on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, where she’ll no doubt be sharing her work on Dicey Dungeons music!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/banner.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;itch.io launch&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this version, &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanagh.itch.io/dicey-dungeons&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons is now on sale for $7.50 on itch.io&lt;/a&gt;! Itch is where I’ll be continuing to post regular alpha versions, every two weeks. The current version on itch.io is still using placeholder art and music, but I’m very excited to be finally implementing Marlowe and Niamh’s work over the past few weeks into the NEXT version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you got in early enough on my discord (way back before v0.7), you’ll be getting a free itch.io code. More details about that on the discord! Oh, and the old alpha versions aren’t going anywhere, btw!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/robot.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Character: The Robot&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this update, I added the game’s fifth character class, &lt;strong&gt;The Robot&lt;/strong&gt;! The robot falls somewhere between the Thief and the Inventor in terms of complexity - definitely easier than the Witch, but definitely harder than the Warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class is all about push your luck mechanics - instead of rolling dice every turn, you have a dice counter that ticks up everytime you &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; to roll a dice. Doing well as the robot means knowing when to roll, and when to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I’m finding the robot super refreshing to play! I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/zh09.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Chinese Localisation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indienova.com/corp/gutenberg/en&quot;&gt;IndieNova&lt;/a&gt; project, there is now a simplified chinese localisation of Dicey Dungeons v0.9 - and one for v0.10 will be coming in a few days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.11?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next update is really exciting for me, because that’s when I’m going to finally start implement Marlowe and Niamh’s work into the game! They’ve both been doing amazing work over the last few weeks, and I can wait to have it in the game and show it all to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Here we are! Version 0.10! The first commercial version! The game’s getting closer and closer to release! Let’s see what’s new.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.9</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/22/version-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.9" /><published>2018-06-22T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/06/22/version-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/06/22/version-9.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey! It’s version 0.9! We’re almost four months in now, gosh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new build is light on new features, but covers some very overdue balance and design changes that I think make the game a lot better. Let’s take a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/newspellbook.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Witch Redesigns&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of changes to the Witch class this time around. She finds more powerful, tempting spells now, and some of the existing powerful Witch spells like Fury and Meteor have been made much cheaper and more viable. Also, it’s now possible to prepare a spell in advance (or two, if you choose the level up perk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Witch is still the most complex class in the game, but I’m hoping these changes make her a little less scary to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/iceage.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Enemy Design Pass&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve wanted to do for a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; long time is a take a step back, and take a fresh look at all the enemies in the game, and how they could be better. So, I did a complete audit! (It’s very long, and full of spoilers, but you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/raw/5AvMgfKa&quot;&gt;read it here if you like&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is major - virtually every enemy in the game has been tweaked. Six old enemies have been removed completely (including two bosses), and there are ten new ones. Also, some existing enemies, like Druid, have changed so much that they’re basically brand new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/cursed.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Status Effects&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following on from v0.8’s elemental magic pass, I did a bunch of work on the Status Effects this time around. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SILENCE:&lt;/strong&gt; Silence prevents you from using your class skills and limit breaks. The big change here is that it can now be broken, for the price of two dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CURSE:&lt;/strong&gt; The old curse effect used to set all your dice to 1, like a freeze all spell. I needed something new here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Curse causes your equipment to fail 50% of the time, forcing you to play carefully and think about what order you’re going to play your equipment in. (I liked how this worked out so much that I make a new guild based around it!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOCK:&lt;/strong&gt; The v0.7 and before times freeze behaviour, which prevented you from using a dice at all, has found a new home as Lock, which is appropriately super rare now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BLIND:&lt;/strong&gt; This new status effect prevents you from seeing the values on your dice - though you can &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; still figure out what they are, depending on what you’ve got equipped…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also fixed a bunch of little things with the elemental attacks - you might find Ice attacks more effective now, for example, since many fewer enemies benefit from having reliable 1s. Shielding and Poison still need a closer look, but I’ll be diving into that for v0.10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/editor.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Editor Improvements&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I did more work on the editor! As well as some UI improvements, you can now create custom enemies, and try fighting against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to do a little work on the editor with every update from now on. I want it to be super easy and fun to make your own levels and mods, right from day 1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/bugtracks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Lots of bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;github issues tracker&lt;/a&gt;, I closed nearly 70 issues over the last two weeks! Still lots more bugs to fix, but the game’s way more stable now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.10?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next update is going to be a big one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one, v0.9 is the last free public build of the game - from v0.10 onwards, I will be &lt;strong&gt;SELLING ALPHA ACCESS&lt;/strong&gt; to the game on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;. I’m also excited to finally introduce the rest of the team - both the game’s artist and musician have recently started working on the game, and I’m can’t wait to show you all what they’ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey! It’s version 0.9! We’re almost four months in now, gosh!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.8</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/08/version-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.8" /><published>2018-06-08T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/06/08/version-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/06/08/version-8.html">&lt;p&gt;At long last, version 0.8! Thanks for bearing with me with this delayed build - I’m very glad I took the extra week to do this new class properly! Let’s have a look at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/witchmoves.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Witch&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So! The Witch! How do I describe the Witch?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The witch is &lt;em&gt;complicated&lt;/em&gt;. Definitely not a class to pick for your first game. In the final version of the game, the Witch will probably be one of the last characters you unlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the witch is also &lt;em&gt;powerful&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike the other classes, the witch isn’t limited to whatever equipment she brings to the fight - the witch has four spell slots, which can be changed at any time. This means that you can, for example, cast four copies of a lockpick spell - and then use the dice you get from &lt;em&gt;THOSE&lt;/em&gt; spells to cast even more spells, which combine and so on and so on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the witch is a class for people who like building unstoppable machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very sure a lot of you are going to hate it, just like I’m very sure it’s going to be some people’s favourite class. I’m so happy with how it’s come together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/elements.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Elemental Magic&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time on this update working on deepening the elemental magic system in the game. A lot of these changes are pretty subtle, but they dramatically improve the range of interesting things that are possible! This is still a work in progress, but here are the big changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIRE:&lt;/strong&gt; All fire attacks now also inflict a &lt;strong&gt;BURN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect. Burn causes your dice to catch fire - you can still use them, but you’ll take some damage if you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICE:&lt;/strong&gt; Ice has been majorly nerfed in v0.8! The &lt;strong&gt;FROZEN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect no longer locks up a dice, but instead changes its value to 1. For some classes, this is devastating - for others, not really a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING:&lt;/strong&gt; The old stun behaviour has basically just been renamed Lightning. &lt;strong&gt;SHOCKING&lt;/strong&gt; an enemy with a lightning spell causes a piece of equipment to lock up! (you can drop a dice on it to release it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EARTH:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, Earth damage, which I’m really happy about - attacking with earth causes a &lt;strong&gt;WEAKEN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect, which downgrades equipment. There’s actually a whole separate downgrade variation for every single piece of equipment in the game now, just like the upgrade variations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while I was at it, I scrapped the concept of poison and elemental immunity from the game, and instead replaced it with resistances, which I think are a lot more interesting. (This should mean that, for example, bringing a fire build against a Dragon isn’t hopeless anymore!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/7drl.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Team Dicey Dungeons&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/blog/2018/05/help-wanted-art-director-for-dicey-dungeons/&quot;&gt;(on my blog)&lt;/a&gt;, that I put up an ad for an Art Director for the game! I got a lot of submissions, and it’s a very tough decision - but I hope to have some news about that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahhhhhh, look at that 7drl screenshot! This game has come such a long way :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.9?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making new content is really fun, but it’s probably about time I slowed down and started fixing some broken stuff. There are over &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;100 open issues on the bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;, including a few crash bugs, so for v0.9 I wanna tackle as many of them as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a good reason for that too. &lt;em&gt;v0.9 will be the LAST free public build of the game&lt;/em&gt; - so I want it to be polished, and stable! I’ll be continuing with this whole open development thing after that, but from behind a paywall (on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;!). I’ll have more information about that next update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in another two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At long last, version 0.8! Thanks for bearing with me with this delayed build - I’m very glad I took the extra week to do this new class properly! Let’s have a look at it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.7</title><link href="/blog/2018/05/18/version-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.7" /><published>2018-05-18T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/05/18/version-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/05/18/version-7.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s here! Version 0.7! Let’s see what’s new this time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/newmap.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Totally Redesigned Dungeon Exploration&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this version, I’ve completely redesigned the exploration phase of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new maps are less than a 5th of the size of the old ones. It’s less complicated, it requires less clicking, and, I think, suits the game much better than the old system. It boils this phase down to pure decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along those lines, other game elements have been simplified too - all the gold values have been reworked (You get exactly one gold per battle now, and equipment tends to cost between 2-5 gold), and experience points match the enemies you’re fighting (a level 2 enemy gives you 2 experience points) - making the game much more boardgamey, and much easier to make strategic decisions about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a bunch of other little structural things - for example, I’ve spread the dungeon out over 5 floors instead of 3 (although it’s actually shorter now thanks to the smaller levels), and it’s all been redesigned so that you don’t need to fight every monster to finish a Dungeon. As a result of all of this, I think the stuff &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of combat is pretty substantially improved in this version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/guild.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Guilds&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best new thing in this update: Guilds! Guilds are my take on roguelike shrine mechanics - they don’t appear everytime you play, but when they do, they’ll offer you some strange wonderful new power… for a price. There a four in the game right now, and I’ll be adding more with each update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably end up reframing guilds in a later version (possibly as something curse themed), but what I’m aiming for is this mechanic where you can take on this extra, bonus challenge for fun. Guilds are always a big risk, but if you go for them, they change up the way you play the game, and open up new kinds of weirder playstyles you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/editor.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Editor Mode&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve implemented a first draft of an in game editor! The current version lets you arm a player with any equipment from the game you want, and fight any of the enemies in the game. Eventually, this mode will let you create full mods and challenges for the game. (It’s already seeing some very cool stuff happen on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;Dicecord&lt;/a&gt; with people trying to make one turn infinite dice builds!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Decisions&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the v0.6 post, I mentioned wanting to catch my breath, and figure out where this whole thing is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve done that. I’ve made some big decisions! Expect a blog post in a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.8?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next update, I’m going to introduce another new class, the &lt;em&gt;Mage&lt;/em&gt;. This class will require a little firming up of some basic combat mechanics, so I’ll probably end up doing quite a lot of work on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in another two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s here! Version 0.7! Let’s see what’s new this time!</summary></entry></feed>