<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-04T22:23:18+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons</title><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.10</title><link href="/blog/2018/07/06/version-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.10" /><published>2018-07-06T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-06T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/07/06/version-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/07/06/version-10.html">&lt;p&gt;Here we are! Version 0.10! The first &lt;strong&gt;commercial&lt;/strong&gt; version! The game’s getting closer and closer to release! Let’s see what’s new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xShpQ85jCVE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons Teaser&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please welcome the rest of team Dicey Dungeons! You can see a little preview of what they’ve been working on in this trailer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/artvart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Art: Marlowe Dobbe&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons new art director is Marlowe Dobbe! Marlowe is an amazing illustrator, animator, and game developer from Portland, Oregon. Her work ranges from animation for the D&amp;amp;D podcast Very Random Encounters, to &lt;a href=&quot;http://marlowe.dobbe.com/lost-wage-rampage&quot;&gt;Lost Wage Rampage&lt;/a&gt;, to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marlowe.dobbe.com/walouija&quot;&gt;WAL-OUIJI board&lt;/a&gt;, which she describes as “a joke that went too far”. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/marlowedobbe/&quot;&gt;check out her instragram here&lt;/a&gt;, where she’ll be posting lots of work in progress Dicey Dungeons artwork over the next few weeks! (she’s also &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marlowedobbe&quot;&gt;on twitter, here&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/chipzel.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Music: Chipzel&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on music, I’m very excited to announce that I’ve teamed up again with Niamh Houston, aka Chipzel! You might know her from her work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://superhexagon.com/&quot;&gt;Super Hexagon&lt;/a&gt; - but she’s also released three albums and worked on all sorts of cool projects, ranging from an Adventure Time game to a remix for Crypt of the NecroDancer. You can find her work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://chipzel.co.uk/&quot;&gt;http://chipzel.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chipzel/&quot;&gt;follow her on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, where she’ll no doubt be sharing her work on Dicey Dungeons music!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/banner.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;itch.io launch&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this version, &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanagh.itch.io/dicey-dungeons&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons is now on sale for $7.50 on itch.io&lt;/a&gt;! Itch is where I’ll be continuing to post regular alpha versions, every two weeks. The current version on itch.io is still using placeholder art and music, but I’m very excited to be finally implementing Marlowe and Niamh’s work over the past few weeks into the NEXT version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you got in early enough on my discord (way back before v0.7), you’ll be getting a free itch.io code. More details about that on the discord! Oh, and the old alpha versions aren’t going anywhere, btw!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/robot.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Character: The Robot&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this update, I added the game’s fifth character class, &lt;strong&gt;The Robot&lt;/strong&gt;! The robot falls somewhere between the Thief and the Inventor in terms of complexity - definitely easier than the Witch, but definitely harder than the Warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class is all about push your luck mechanics - instead of rolling dice every turn, you have a dice counter that ticks up everytime you &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; to roll a dice. Doing well as the robot means knowing when to roll, and when to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I’m finding the robot super refreshing to play! I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version10/zh09.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Chinese Localisation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indienova.com/corp/gutenberg/en&quot;&gt;IndieNova&lt;/a&gt; project, there is now a simplified chinese localisation of Dicey Dungeons v0.9 - and one for v0.10 will be coming in a few days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.11?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next update is really exciting for me, because that’s when I’m going to finally start implement Marlowe and Niamh’s work into the game! They’ve both been doing amazing work over the last few weeks, and I can wait to have it in the game and show it all to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Here we are! Version 0.10! The first commercial version! The game’s getting closer and closer to release! Let’s see what’s new.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.9</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/22/version-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.9" /><published>2018-06-22T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/06/22/version-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/06/22/version-9.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey! It’s version 0.9! We’re almost four months in now, gosh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new build is light on new features, but covers some very overdue balance and design changes that I think make the game a lot better. Let’s take a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/newspellbook.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Witch Redesigns&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of changes to the Witch class this time around. She finds more powerful, tempting spells now, and some of the existing powerful Witch spells like Fury and Meteor have been made much cheaper and more viable. Also, it’s now possible to prepare a spell in advance (or two, if you choose the level up perk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Witch is still the most complex class in the game, but I’m hoping these changes make her a little less scary to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/iceage.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Enemy Design Pass&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve wanted to do for a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; long time is a take a step back, and take a fresh look at all the enemies in the game, and how they could be better. So, I did a complete audit! (It’s very long, and full of spoilers, but you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://pastebin.com/raw/5AvMgfKa&quot;&gt;read it here if you like&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is major - virtually every enemy in the game has been tweaked. Six old enemies have been removed completely (including two bosses), and there are ten new ones. Also, some existing enemies, like Druid, have changed so much that they’re basically brand new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/cursed.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Status Effects&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following on from v0.8’s elemental magic pass, I did a bunch of work on the Status Effects this time around. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SILENCE:&lt;/strong&gt; Silence prevents you from using your class skills and limit breaks. The big change here is that it can now be broken, for the price of two dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CURSE:&lt;/strong&gt; The old curse effect used to set all your dice to 1, like a freeze all spell. I needed something new here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Curse causes your equipment to fail 50% of the time, forcing you to play carefully and think about what order you’re going to play your equipment in. (I liked how this worked out so much that I make a new guild based around it!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOCK:&lt;/strong&gt; The v0.7 and before times freeze behaviour, which prevented you from using a dice at all, has found a new home as Lock, which is appropriately super rare now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BLIND:&lt;/strong&gt; This new status effect prevents you from seeing the values on your dice - though you can &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; still figure out what they are, depending on what you’ve got equipped…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also fixed a bunch of little things with the elemental attacks - you might find Ice attacks more effective now, for example, since many fewer enemies benefit from having reliable 1s. Shielding and Poison still need a closer look, but I’ll be diving into that for v0.10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/editor.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Editor Improvements&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I did more work on the editor! As well as some UI improvements, you can now create custom enemies, and try fighting against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to do a little work on the editor with every update from now on. I want it to be super easy and fun to make your own levels and mods, right from day 1!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version9/bugtracks.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Lots of bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;github issues tracker&lt;/a&gt;, I closed nearly 70 issues over the last two weeks! Still lots more bugs to fix, but the game’s way more stable now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.10?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next update is going to be a big one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one, v0.9 is the last free public build of the game - from v0.10 onwards, I will be &lt;strong&gt;SELLING ALPHA ACCESS&lt;/strong&gt; to the game on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;. I’m also excited to finally introduce the rest of the team - both the game’s artist and musician have recently started working on the game, and I’m can’t wait to show you all what they’ve been up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey! It’s version 0.9! We’re almost four months in now, gosh!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.8</title><link href="/blog/2018/06/08/version-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.8" /><published>2018-06-08T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/06/08/version-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/06/08/version-8.html">&lt;p&gt;At long last, version 0.8! Thanks for bearing with me with this delayed build - I’m very glad I took the extra week to do this new class properly! Let’s have a look at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/witchmoves.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Witch&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So! The Witch! How do I describe the Witch?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The witch is &lt;em&gt;complicated&lt;/em&gt;. Definitely not a class to pick for your first game. In the final version of the game, the Witch will probably be one of the last characters you unlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the witch is also &lt;em&gt;powerful&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike the other classes, the witch isn’t limited to whatever equipment she brings to the fight - the witch has four spell slots, which can be changed at any time. This means that you can, for example, cast four copies of a lockpick spell - and then use the dice you get from &lt;em&gt;THOSE&lt;/em&gt; spells to cast even more spells, which combine and so on and so on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the witch is a class for people who like building unstoppable machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very sure a lot of you are going to hate it, just like I’m very sure it’s going to be some people’s favourite class. I’m so happy with how it’s come together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/elements.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Elemental Magic&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time on this update working on deepening the elemental magic system in the game. A lot of these changes are pretty subtle, but they dramatically improve the range of interesting things that are possible! This is still a work in progress, but here are the big changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIRE:&lt;/strong&gt; All fire attacks now also inflict a &lt;strong&gt;BURN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect. Burn causes your dice to catch fire - you can still use them, but you’ll take some damage if you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ICE:&lt;/strong&gt; Ice has been majorly nerfed in v0.8! The &lt;strong&gt;FROZEN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect no longer locks up a dice, but instead changes its value to 1. For some classes, this is devastating - for others, not really a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIGHTNING:&lt;/strong&gt; The old stun behaviour has basically just been renamed Lightning. &lt;strong&gt;SHOCKING&lt;/strong&gt; an enemy with a lightning spell causes a piece of equipment to lock up! (you can drop a dice on it to release it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EARTH:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, Earth damage, which I’m really happy about - attacking with earth causes a &lt;strong&gt;WEAKEN&lt;/strong&gt; status effect, which downgrades equipment. There’s actually a whole separate downgrade variation for every single piece of equipment in the game now, just like the upgrade variations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while I was at it, I scrapped the concept of poison and elemental immunity from the game, and instead replaced it with resistances, which I think are a lot more interesting. (This should mean that, for example, bringing a fire build against a Dragon isn’t hopeless anymore!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version8/7drl.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Team Dicey Dungeons&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have seen &lt;a href=&quot;http://distractionware.com/blog/2018/05/help-wanted-art-director-for-dicey-dungeons/&quot;&gt;(on my blog)&lt;/a&gt;, that I put up an ad for an Art Director for the game! I got a lot of submissions, and it’s a very tough decision - but I hope to have some news about that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahhhhhh, look at that 7drl screenshot! This game has come such a long way :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.9?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making new content is really fun, but it’s probably about time I slowed down and started fixing some broken stuff. There are over &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;100 open issues on the bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;, including a few crash bugs, so for v0.9 I wanna tackle as many of them as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a good reason for that too. &lt;em&gt;v0.9 will be the LAST free public build of the game&lt;/em&gt; - so I want it to be polished, and stable! I’ll be continuing with this whole open development thing after that, but from behind a paywall (on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/&quot;&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt;!). I’ll have more information about that next update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in another two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At long last, version 0.8! Thanks for bearing with me with this delayed build - I’m very glad I took the extra week to do this new class properly! Let’s have a look at it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.7</title><link href="/blog/2018/05/18/version-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.7" /><published>2018-05-18T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/05/18/version-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/05/18/version-7.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s here! Version 0.7! Let’s see what’s new this time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/newmap.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Totally Redesigned Dungeon Exploration&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this version, I’ve completely redesigned the exploration phase of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new maps are less than a 5th of the size of the old ones. It’s less complicated, it requires less clicking, and, I think, suits the game much better than the old system. It boils this phase down to pure decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along those lines, other game elements have been simplified too - all the gold values have been reworked (You get exactly one gold per battle now, and equipment tends to cost between 2-5 gold), and experience points match the enemies you’re fighting (a level 2 enemy gives you 2 experience points) - making the game much more boardgamey, and much easier to make strategic decisions about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a bunch of other little structural things - for example, I’ve spread the dungeon out over 5 floors instead of 3 (although it’s actually shorter now thanks to the smaller levels), and it’s all been redesigned so that you don’t need to fight every monster to finish a Dungeon. As a result of all of this, I think the stuff &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; of combat is pretty substantially improved in this version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/guild.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Guilds&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best new thing in this update: Guilds! Guilds are my take on roguelike shrine mechanics - they don’t appear everytime you play, but when they do, they’ll offer you some strange wonderful new power… for a price. There a four in the game right now, and I’ll be adding more with each update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably end up reframing guilds in a later version (possibly as something curse themed), but what I’m aiming for is this mechanic where you can take on this extra, bonus challenge for fun. Guilds are always a big risk, but if you go for them, they change up the way you play the game, and open up new kinds of weirder playstyles you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version7/editor.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Editor Mode&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve implemented a first draft of an in game editor! The current version lets you arm a player with any equipment from the game you want, and fight any of the enemies in the game. Eventually, this mode will let you create full mods and challenges for the game. (It’s already seeing some very cool stuff happen on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;Dicecord&lt;/a&gt; with people trying to make one turn infinite dice builds!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Decisions&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the v0.6 post, I mentioned wanting to catch my breath, and figure out where this whole thing is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ve done that. I’ve made some big decisions! Expect a blog post in a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;So what about v0.8?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next update, I’m going to introduce another new class, the &lt;em&gt;Mage&lt;/em&gt;. This class will require a little firming up of some basic combat mechanics, so I’ll probably end up doing quite a lot of work on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in another two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s here! Version 0.7! Let’s see what’s new this time!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.6</title><link href="/blog/2018/05/04/version-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.6" /><published>2018-05-04T03:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-04T03:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/05/04/version-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/05/04/version-6.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey again! It’s v0.6! I’d sorta planned that this one would be a smaller update, since I was travelling for a bit of it. But it ended up being HUGE. Let’s jump in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version6/characters.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Character: The Inventor&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured it was time I tried out some weirder character ideas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Inventor&lt;/em&gt; is a new class focused on abilities that you get for one fight only, called gadgets. (Gadgets replace items.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Inventor is a class with some pretty big pros and cons - on the plus side, they get gadgets, which are super powerful, and they find some of the most powerful equipment in the game just lying around. However! The Inventor’s compulsive need to tinker with things results it in scrapping most of your equipment for parts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing the Inventor well requires thinking ahead and planning what you think you’ll need, and what you think you can do without. I hope you enjoy it! Like everything in the game, it’s a work in progress, and should improve as time goes by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version6/snowman.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Warrior&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pretty major changes to the Warrior this time - they’ve lost the ability to use items, which are now redesigned as “gadgets”, and are unique to the new Inventor class. However, to compensate, they get a new dice tweak ability to go with their reroll skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want Warrior to be the introductory class, so the changes I’ve made &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; make it easier. As well as the skill change, they also find more powerful equipment, and there are a load of tweaks to add variety to the range of viable builds you can try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The thief has also had a few tweaks, but they’re a lot less dramatic.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version6/rogue.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New enemies, and new Enemy AI&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent almost a week of this fortnight on Enemy AI - it’s had a complete rewrite! Enemies can handle much more complicated situations now, allowing them to do new things like use reusable equipment, and make decisions about dice to set aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s enabled me to make a couple of more sophisticated enemies to match, so this build introduces &lt;strong&gt;five new enemies&lt;/strong&gt;, and a new &lt;strong&gt;final boss&lt;/strong&gt;, the Crime Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version6/limitbreak.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Limit Breaks&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New mechanic I’m trying out: Limit Breaks! Each character has a special skill that they can use once they’ve taken enough damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's the plan for v0.7?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m long overdue a polish update, so for v0.7 I’m planning to slow down a little, and do some work on balance, polish and structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are going pretty well! I think it’s time I made some decisions about where this is all going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing! See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey again! It’s v0.6! I’d sorta planned that this one would be a smaller update, since I was travelling for a bit of it. But it ended up being HUGE. Let’s jump in!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.5</title><link href="/blog/2018/04/20/version-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.5" /><published>2018-04-20T08:53:04+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T08:53:04+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/04/20/version-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/04/20/version-5.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s version 0.5! Whoa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome! If you’re dropping by for the first time, here’s what’s going on: &lt;em&gt;Dicey Dungeons&lt;/em&gt; is a game I started making for this year’s 7 day roguelike. It’s now a month and a half on, I’m still working on it, and it’s going very well! The game’s basically a roguelike inspired by Dream Quest and games like that - only it’s designed around dice instead of cards. You explore a dungeon, you find equipment, and you use dice on that equipment to activate it. I think it’s already pretty fun, and it’s getting better with every update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m releasing new work in progress builds every two weeks. Here’s what I’ve been working on since the last update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version5/apprentice.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;I finally made some graphics&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a long time coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to a two week schedule gives me more freedom to work on larger stuff for the game. This week, I used that extra time to finally add some graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still a bit rough in places, but I should be able to iterate on this stuff now and improve it as the weeks go by and LOOK LOOK, the little dice people have stubby little legs and big smiles! Aren’t they’re cute? Awwww&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version5/thiefvswolfpuppy.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Equipment fires without needing a confirmation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two very radical changes to how equipment works this week: you need to fill all dice slots on a piece of equipment to use it, and equipment fires automatically once all the slots are full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like a tiny change, but it has a pretty massive knock on effect to lots of things in the game. And I think it’s worth it! For me, the game just feels &lt;em&gt;substantially&lt;/em&gt; nicer to play with this change - I can’t go back to the old v0.4 way at all after this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular this makes the Thief class a lot nicer to play - way less finicky mouse movement to trigger reusable equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version5/upgrades.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New upgrade system&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old upgrade system was designed around the Warrior, but the new equipment UI rules broke it completely. So, I tried something new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new upgrade system is inspired by fellow dreamquestlike &lt;strong&gt;Slay the Spire&lt;/strong&gt; - every piece of equipment in the game can now be upgraded, and the effect of upgrading is unique to each piece of equipment. Upgrading the &lt;em&gt;Dagger&lt;/em&gt; gives it bonus +1 damage, for example, while upgrading the &lt;em&gt;Poison Needle&lt;/em&gt; lets it accept a broader range of dice, making it easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version5/hardmode.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Hard Mode&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;v0.5 has a new HARD MODE! In this version, all enemy equipment is upgraded, and enemies get an extra 20% health. If you’ve been around since the start and find the game a bit easy now, this should provide a more interesting challenge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version5/optimised.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Optimisation&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons was hacked together for a game jam, and that meant that it was running quite a lot slower than it should have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a big optimisation pass this week that should substantially improve things - in my profiler tests, I was getting frame time reductions of up to 500%, depending on what was happening in the game at the time. There’s more I can do about this later, but these optimisations should leave the game a lot more stable and lightweight from here on out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's the plan for v0.6?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I’m off to &lt;a href=&quot;http://amaze-berlin.de/&quot;&gt;AMAZE&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin, so I’m expecting a slightly smaller than normal update. To be honest, this feels like a good time to catch my breath, and figure out where this whole thing is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I’d really like to get to work on a new class for the next update - I think the Thief is working really well, and I eventually see there being 5 or 6 classes in the final version. Let’s see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s version 0.5! Whoa!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.4</title><link href="/blog/2018/04/06/version-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.4" /><published>2018-04-06T08:53:04+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T08:53:04+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/04/06/version-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/04/06/version-4.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey! It’s v0.4! This is the biggest update so far. Let’s jump right in! Here’s what’s new:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/thief.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Thief&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s update is all about the new class, the &lt;em&gt;Thief&lt;/em&gt;. The Thief is pretty different from the warrior - it doesn’t get upgrades, it can’t use consumable items, and it can’t reroll - instead, it has to rely on it’s handy steal ability, which takes a random piece of enemy equipment every turn, and a bunch of new class specific equipment. The Thief class is a bit harder than the Warrior too, so good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/bandit.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Fleeing from Combat&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things not going according to plan? You can now flee from any battle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/skeleton.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four new enemies in this build, and lots of the existing enemies have gotten tweaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there is now a designated boss on EVERY FLOOR, not just the final one. Some of the harder enemies have gotten a promotion! (If you’re wondering about where the Knight is this time round, they’re taking a holiday while I figure out how to redesign it as a new sub-boss!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Rat King has gotten a big level up, and there’s a brand new final boss this time around - the Vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/wizard.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Loads of bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than two dozen bug fixes, mostly stuff reported from v0.3! Dicey Dungeons doesn’t have any in-game issue tracking yet, but you can submit bugs and feature requests &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;on the github page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to replace the bugs that we’ve lost in this build, I’ve added several new ones. See if you can find them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/tapcontrols.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Tap Controls&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thief uses a lot more dice than the warrior, and all that dragging was starting to get a bit tiring. So this time I’m trying out alternate tap controls - you can now just tap a dice, and then tap the piece of equipment you want to assign it to. This probably needs a bit more tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have vague plans that this thing will eventually end up on telephones, so will be experimenting a lot more with things like this as the weeks go by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for checking out the latest build. For the next update, I’m hoping to focus on balance, polish, and at long last, ART. See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey! It’s v0.4! This is the biggest update so far. Let’s jump right in! Here’s what’s new:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.3</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/30/version-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.3" /><published>2018-03-30T08:53:04+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T08:53:04+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/30/version-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/30/version-3.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey hey, it’s update 0.3!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week’s build was probably too easy. This one is definitely too hard. So it goes - it’s still very, very early days for this game. I’ll figure it out eventually! &lt;strong&gt;YAY FOR OPEN DEVELOPMENT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still lots of bugs in this build, including stuff that was reported last week. Honestly, this is the thing I’m finding hardest about this whole early-access-like thing I’m doing - my impulse is not to release anything until I know it’s all fixed and working and balanced - but I’m trying not to do that with this. Eventually, this game will start to firm up, and hopefully you’ll see it happen. Week after week. One version at a time. Bear with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new in v0.3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/spreadsheets.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;A balance pass&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything&lt;/em&gt; in the game has gotten a tweak this week - from enemies to equipment, level up distributions to level layouts - you name it. Some existing systems have been tweaked too - for example, the upgrade system is very different from last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is an ongoing process that’s going to take time to get right, but I think this build is a step in the right direction - towards a version of the game I want to make: a deeper, more rewarding, more fun experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/newcontent.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Loads of new content&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This build brings a ton of new content. There are about 25 new pieces of equipment in the game this time round, as well as a bunch of new enemies, items and shops. A lot of this is because there are new &lt;strong&gt;types&lt;/strong&gt; of diceslots on equipment boards - &lt;strong&gt;Doubles&lt;/strong&gt;, which require matching dice to trigger, and &lt;strong&gt;Countdowns&lt;/strong&gt;, which take any dice and need to hit a target amount before they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/ratking.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Bosses&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re good enough to get to the end of the dungeon, the final battle in 0.3 is one of three possible bosses. They’re all pretty tough. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's next?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I finally want to make some progress on a second class! This doesn’t mean that I’m done with the Warrior, far from it - but I think I’m at the point where designing a seperate path through the game will push things along in lots of unexplored directions, and do way more for the game than continuing to tweak the existing content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok! Hope you enjoy this version! See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey hey, it’s update 0.3!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.2</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.2" /><published>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/23/version-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Welcome back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m attempting to do this early access like thing where I release builds publically every week, warts and all. I’ve never done this before - actually, it makes me pretty nervous to show work that I don’t think is ready yet. But I think it’s worth trying to get over that, because it’s clearly a good approach for this project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons is still pretty rough. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; early in development, after all. However, I think this week’s build shows that things are starting to take shape, and I hope you all like where it’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new with 0.2 of Dicey Dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/newui.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;UI Makeover&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most noticable change in the new build, I made a start at doing some proper graphics for the game! Hopefully things are a bit more legible now, and nicer to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/healthshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Money and Shops&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest gameplay change this time around is the addition of Gold and Shops to the game. There’s at least one shop on every floor, which sell various items, equipment and bonuses. (They’re not really balanced yet, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/upgrade.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Equipment Upgrading&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying out another new system in this build, Equipment Upgrading! Most weapons and armour can be upgraded now, which adds a permanent dice to that piece of equipment everytime you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s currently pretty over powered, so check it out before I nerf it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/itemshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Item System&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the biggest problems with the 7drl version: The Warrior’s &lt;b&gt;Rage&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Focus&lt;/b&gt; skills didn’t work, because associating a HP cost with them made ‘em too expensive, and single use items weren’t worth equipping, because it was never worth sacrificing an inventory space for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution to both problems is a new item system! Now, items are kept seperately from your inventory, and take the place of the second and third warrior skills. Eventually, different classes might have different skill/item layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything else here, this’ll be getting refined and improved as the weeks go by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/banshee.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Equipment and Enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lot of new equipment (e.g. Claws), enemies (e.g. Banshee) and status effects (e.g. Silence) in there. Some of the existing equipment and enemies have been removed (Yeti) or redesigned (Squire). I forgot to fix the Knight though, sorry D:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's next?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying not to plan more than a week ahead right now, but my next big goal with the game is to add another class, the Thief. That’s gonna wait until after this week though, because next, I’d like to slow down a bit and start properly balancing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots of stuff in the game now, but none of it is really balanced properly yet. I don’t think I can really go much further until I get a handle on that. So! Week three! Balance update! See you next friday!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey everyone! Welcome back!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)" /><published>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/12/version-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version1/day7.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! I made a game for this year’s 7 Day Roguelike. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/7drl-challenge-2018/rate/234586&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons&lt;/a&gt; and you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanaghgames.com/dice/&quot;&gt;go play it right now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only… well, it’s a bit broken. So much so that I freaked out a little bit about sharing it publicly at first. These days, I usually keep pretty quiet about prototypes - it’s been a long time since I shared something this rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, &lt;i&gt;I really like this game&lt;/i&gt;. I think with a bit more work, this currently broken idea of a game could be really, really great. So I’m going to spend a little more time on it. Give it another two weeks. See where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does means putting State Machine on hold for a few weeks, but I think that’s probably a good thing. Ruari and I have been working solidly on that for close to two and a half years, and I think we’re overdue a little creative break. (Ruari’s actually working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/randomnine/status/965324342996471808&quot;&gt;a very cool sideproject of his own&lt;/a&gt; that he should have some news about soon…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to be a bit more open about the development of this, &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;so I’ve set up a discord?&lt;/a&gt; Yeah, I dunno, I just thought I’d try it! DICE PLANET.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>