<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-28T10:02:53+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons</title><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.2</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.2" /><published>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/23/version-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Welcome back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m attempting to do this early access like thing where I release builds publically every week, warts and all. I’ve never done this before - actually, it makes me pretty nervous to show work that I don’t think is ready yet. But I think it’s worth trying to get over that, because it’s clearly a good approach for this project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons is still pretty rough. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; early in development, after all. However, I think this week’s build shows that things are starting to take shape, and I hope you all like where it’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new with 0.2 of Dicey Dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/newui.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;UI Makeover&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most noticable change in the new build, I made a start at doing some proper graphics for the game! Hopefully things are a bit more legible now, and nicer to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/healthshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Money and Shops&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest gameplay change this time around is the addition of Gold and Shops to the game. There’s at least one shop on every floor, which sell various items, equipment and bonuses. (They’re not really balanced yet, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/upgrade.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Equipment Upgrading&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying out another new system in this build, Equipment Upgrading! Most weapons and armour can be upgraded now, which adds a permanent dice to that piece of equipment everytime you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s currently pretty over powered, so check it out before I nerf it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/itemshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Item System&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the biggest problems with the 7drl version: The Warrior’s &lt;b&gt;Rage&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Focus&lt;/b&gt; skills didn’t work, because associating a HP cost with them made ‘em too expensive, and single use items weren’t worth equipping, because it was never worth sacrificing an inventory space for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution to both problems is a new item system! Now, items are kept seperately from your inventory, and take the place of the second and third warrior skills. Eventually, different classes might have different skill/item layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything else here, this’ll be getting refined and improved as the weeks go by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/banshee.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Equipment and Enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lot of new equipment (e.g. Claws), enemies (e.g. Banshee) and status effects (e.g. Silence) in there. Some of the existing equipment and enemies have been removed (Yeti) or redesigned (Squire). I forgot to fix the Knight though, sorry D:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's next?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying not to plan more than a week ahead right now, but my next big goal with the game is to add another class, the Thief. That’s gonna wait until after this week though, because next, I’d like to slow down a bit and start properly balancing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots of stuff in the game now, but none of it is really balanced properly yet. I don’t think I can really go much further until I get a handle on that. So! Week three! Balance update! See you next friday!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey everyone! Welcome back!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)" /><published>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/12/version-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version1/day7.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! I made a game for this year’s 7 Day Roguelike. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/7drl-challenge-2018/rate/234586&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons&lt;/a&gt; and you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanaghgames.com/dice/&quot;&gt;go play it right now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only… well, it’s a bit broken. So much so that I freaked out a little bit about sharing it publicly at first. These days, I usually keep pretty quiet about prototypes - it’s been a long time since I shared something this rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, &lt;i&gt;I really like this game&lt;/i&gt;. I think with a bit more work, this currently broken idea of a game could be really, really great. So I’m going to spend a little more time on it. Give it another two weeks. See where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does means putting State Machine on hold for a few weeks, but I think that’s probably a good thing. Ruari and I have been working solidly on that for close to two and a half years, and I think we’re overdue a little creative break. (Ruari’s actually working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/randomnine/status/965324342996471808&quot;&gt;a very cool sideproject of his own&lt;/a&gt; that he should have some news about soon…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to be a bit more open about the development of this, &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;so I’ve set up a discord?&lt;/a&gt; Yeah, I dunno, I just thought I’d try it! DICE PLANET.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>