<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-10T19:52:57+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons</title><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.4</title><link href="/blog/2018/04/06/version-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.4" /><published>2018-04-06T08:53:04+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T08:53:04+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/04/06/version-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/04/06/version-4.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey! It’s v0.4! This is the biggest update so far. Let’s jump right in! Here’s what’s new:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/thief.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;The Thief&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s update is all about the new class, the &lt;em&gt;Thief&lt;/em&gt;. The Thief is pretty different from the warrior - it doesn’t get upgrades, it can’t use consumable items, and it can’t reroll - instead, it has to rely on it’s handy steal ability, which takes a random piece of enemy equipment every turn, and a bunch of new class specific equipment. The Thief class is a bit harder than the Warrior too, so good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/bandit.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Fleeing from Combat&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things not going according to plan? You can now flee from any battle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/skeleton.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four new enemies in this build, and lots of the existing enemies have gotten tweaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there is now a designated boss on EVERY FLOOR, not just the final one. Some of the harder enemies have gotten a promotion! (If you’re wondering about where the Knight is this time round, they’re taking a holiday while I figure out how to redesign it as a new sub-boss!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Rat King has gotten a big level up, and there’s a brand new final boss this time around - the Vampire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/wizard.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Loads of bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than two dozen bug fixes, mostly stuff reported from v0.3! Dicey Dungeons doesn’t have any in-game issue tracking yet, but you can submit bugs and feature requests &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TerryCavanagh/diceydungeons.com/issues&quot;&gt;on the github page here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to replace the bugs that we’ve lost in this build, I’ve added several new ones. See if you can find them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version4/tapcontrols.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Tap Controls&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thief uses a lot more dice than the warrior, and all that dragging was starting to get a bit tiring. So this time I’m trying out alternate tap controls - you can now just tap a dice, and then tap the piece of equipment you want to assign it to. This probably needs a bit more tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have vague plans that this thing will eventually end up on telephones, so will be experimenting a lot more with things like this as the weeks go by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for checking out the latest build. For the next update, I’m hoping to focus on balance, polish, and at long last, ART. See you in two weeks!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey! It’s v0.4! This is the biggest update so far. Let’s jump right in! Here’s what’s new:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.3</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/30/version-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.3" /><published>2018-03-30T08:53:04+01:00</published><updated>2018-03-30T08:53:04+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/30/version-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/30/version-3.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey hey, it’s update 0.3!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week’s build was probably too easy. This one is definitely too hard. So it goes - it’s still very, very early days for this game. I’ll figure it out eventually! &lt;strong&gt;YAY FOR OPEN DEVELOPMENT!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still lots of bugs in this build, including stuff that was reported last week. Honestly, this is the thing I’m finding hardest about this whole early-access-like thing I’m doing - my impulse is not to release anything until I know it’s all fixed and working and balanced - but I’m trying not to do that with this. Eventually, this game will start to firm up, and hopefully you’ll see it happen. Week after week. One version at a time. Bear with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new in v0.3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/spreadsheets.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;A balance pass&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything&lt;/em&gt; in the game has gotten a tweak this week - from enemies to equipment, level up distributions to level layouts - you name it. Some existing systems have been tweaked too - for example, the upgrade system is very different from last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balance is an ongoing process that’s going to take time to get right, but I think this build is a step in the right direction - towards a version of the game I want to make: a deeper, more rewarding, more fun experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/newcontent.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Loads of new content&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This build brings a ton of new content. There are about 25 new pieces of equipment in the game this time round, as well as a bunch of new enemies, items and shops. A lot of this is because there are new &lt;strong&gt;types&lt;/strong&gt; of diceslots on equipment boards - &lt;strong&gt;Doubles&lt;/strong&gt;, which require matching dice to trigger, and &lt;strong&gt;Countdowns&lt;/strong&gt;, which take any dice and need to hit a target amount before they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version3/ratking.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Bosses&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re good enough to get to the end of the dungeon, the final battle in 0.3 is one of three possible bosses. They’re all pretty tough. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's next?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I finally want to make some progress on a second class! This doesn’t mean that I’m done with the Warrior, far from it - but I think I’m at the point where designing a seperate path through the game will push things along in lots of unexplored directions, and do way more for the game than continuing to tweak the existing content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok! Hope you enjoy this version! See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey hey, it’s update 0.3!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.2</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.2" /><published>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-23T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/23/version-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/23/version-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Welcome back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m attempting to do this early access like thing where I release builds publically every week, warts and all. I’ve never done this before - actually, it makes me pretty nervous to show work that I don’t think is ready yet. But I think it’s worth trying to get over that, because it’s clearly a good approach for this project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dicey Dungeons is still pretty rough. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; early in development, after all. However, I think this week’s build shows that things are starting to take shape, and I hope you all like where it’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new with 0.2 of Dicey Dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/newui.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold; margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;UI Makeover&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most noticable change in the new build, I made a start at doing some proper graphics for the game! Hopefully things are a bit more legible now, and nicer to look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/healthshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Money and Shops&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest gameplay change this time around is the addition of Gold and Shops to the game. There’s at least one shop on every floor, which sell various items, equipment and bonuses. (They’re not really balanced yet, though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/upgrade.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;Equipment Upgrading&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying out another new system in this build, Equipment Upgrading! Most weapons and armour can be upgraded now, which adds a permanent dice to that piece of equipment everytime you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s currently pretty over powered, so check it out before I nerf it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/itemshop.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Item System&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the biggest problems with the 7drl version: The Warrior’s &lt;b&gt;Rage&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Focus&lt;/b&gt; skills didn’t work, because associating a HP cost with them made ‘em too expensive, and single use items weren’t worth equipping, because it was never worth sacrificing an inventory space for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution to both problems is a new item system! Now, items are kept seperately from your inventory, and take the place of the second and third warrior skills. Eventually, different classes might have different skill/item layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything else here, this’ll be getting refined and improved as the weeks go by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version2/banshee.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;  margin-top: -3%;&quot;&gt;New Equipment and Enemies&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lot of new equipment (e.g. Claws), enemies (e.g. Banshee) and status effects (e.g. Silence) in there. Some of the existing equipment and enemies have been removed (Yeti) or redesigned (Squire). I forgot to fix the Knight though, sorry D:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; font-size: large; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;What's next?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying not to plan more than a week ahead right now, but my next big goal with the game is to add another class, the Thief. That’s gonna wait until after this week though, because next, I’d like to slow down a bit and start properly balancing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots of stuff in the game now, but none of it is really balanced properly yet. I don’t think I can really go much further until I get a handle on that. So! Week three! Balance update! See you next friday!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey everyone! Welcome back!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)</title><link href="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dicey Dungeons 0.1 (7drl)" /><published>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-12T07:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2018/03/12/version-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2018/03/12/version-1.html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/version1/day7.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! I made a game for this year’s 7 Day Roguelike. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch.io/jam/7drl-challenge-2018/rate/234586&quot;&gt;Dicey Dungeons&lt;/a&gt; and you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://terrycavanaghgames.com/dice/&quot;&gt;go play it right now&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only… well, it’s a bit broken. So much so that I freaked out a little bit about sharing it publicly at first. These days, I usually keep pretty quiet about prototypes - it’s been a long time since I shared something this rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, &lt;i&gt;I really like this game&lt;/i&gt;. I think with a bit more work, this currently broken idea of a game could be really, really great. So I’m going to spend a little more time on it. Give it another two weeks. See where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does means putting State Machine on hold for a few weeks, but I think that’s probably a good thing. Ruari and I have been working solidly on that for close to two and a half years, and I think we’re overdue a little creative break. (Ruari’s actually working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/randomnine/status/965324342996471808&quot;&gt;a very cool sideproject of his own&lt;/a&gt; that he should have some news about soon…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to be a bit more open about the development of this, &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/z7pCdCP&quot;&gt;so I’ve set up a discord?&lt;/a&gt; Yeah, I dunno, I just thought I’d try it! DICE PLANET.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>